<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sensu Plugins</title>
    <description>The home for all Sensu Official and Community plugins, handlers, extensions and mutators.
</description>
    <link>http://sensu-plugins.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://sensu-plugins.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 04:08:25 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 04:08:25 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to new Sensu Plugins!</title>
        <description>
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2015 22:20:18 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sensu-plugins.github.io/sensu-plugins/update/2015/01/26/welcome-to-sensu-plugins-new-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sensu-plugins.github.io/sensu-plugins/update/2015/01/26/welcome-to-sensu-plugins-new-home.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>sensu-plugins</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sensu Plugins Roadmap</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sensu/sensu-community-plugins/issues/847&quot;&gt;Issue #847&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Packaging and versioning of the plugins is something I know a lot of people want and for good reason.  I would like to purpose a thought and see how people feel about it. In a nutshell I would like to split the community-plugins repo in smaller repos, based upon application.  This would mean all the Windows plugins, handlers, etc would go into a repo named &lt;strong&gt;sensu-plugins-windows&lt;/strong&gt;, the aws ones would go to &lt;strong&gt;sensu-plugins-aws&lt;/strong&gt; and so one. Some projects already do this to some extent, specifically Hubot, and it presents many advantages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pros&quot;&gt;Pros&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Application groups are easier to package and version than a monolithic repository&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Plugin groups could be installed by an automation tool or Sensu itself with ease and be dependent upon only those checks currently running&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There would be no need to bump the entire plugins repo for a small change to a single plugin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A user could pin separate gem versions depending on their environment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cons&quot;&gt;Cons&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More overhead concerning dependency management&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More jobs to create and manage&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Plugin groups may not work for everyone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those that want things the way they are we will create quarterly meta-gem releases of all the various gems, and these can be considered stable, whereas the individual gems could be considered production grade but active and the meta-gem would get built from each of these. This paves the way for company’s to create specific gemsets for only the software they run. For example a lamp stack meta-gem would consist of core(system), mysql, and apache.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dependency management could be somewhat solved over time as the community builds custom meta sets and such that all rely on a single dependency version, as they pin their version and run the included integration tests, if they pass then they could submit a PR back and we could bump the dependency for that specific gem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;proposed-timeframe&quot;&gt;Proposed Timeframe&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;February (Creation)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Split all repos&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Create gems for each repo as they currently stand&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;March - April (Transition Period)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Maintain both architectures&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Accept pull requests from &lt;strong&gt;sensu-community-plugins&lt;/strong&gt; repo and new repos&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Create build schedule and pipeline for new gems&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;May (Start cutover)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stop accepting PR’s and issues for &lt;strong&gt;sensu-community-plugins&lt;/strong&gt; repo for new functionality (bugs and security fixes still allowed)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Maintain desired build schedule for all new gems&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;June (End cutover)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Freeze &lt;strong&gt;sensu-community-plugins&lt;/strong&gt; repo and stop accepting all PR’s and Issues&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Maintain desired build schedule for all new gems&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create first unstable release of meta-gem package&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2015 22:20:18 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sensu-plugins.github.io/sensu-plugins/issue/2015/01/26/sensu-plugins-roadmap.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sensu-plugins.github.io/sensu-plugins/issue/2015/01/26/sensu-plugins-roadmap.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>sensu-plugins</category>
        
        <category>issue</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
